# VÍTOR TEIXEIRA

#### USER EXPERIENCE PROFESSIONAL

I'm a User Experience Professional with a passion for solving problems with smart and simple user-centered design. Passionate about life and technology, my goal is to make sure the latter does not get in the way of the former, but instead makes it better.

## > WORK EXPERIENCE

OUTSYSTEMS

Mar 2018 - Present

#### LEAD PRODUCT DESIGNER

Led a Design and Research team working with several Product Teams. Pioneered a lean and user-centered approach to Product Discovery. Helped implementing a Dual-Track agile process to start informing the delivery backlog early, with more confidence and less risk. Conducted several field and remote user studies. Designed, developed and tested mid-fidelity and hi-fidelity prototypes.

MAIN PROJECTS: Service Studio - IDE | OutSystems UI Framework

SKYSTORE SKY Ltd

Feb 2016 - Feb 2018

#### **USER EXPERIENCE ENGINEER**

Bridged collaboration between London's UX team and Dev team in Lisbon. Designed, developed and tested mid-fidelity and hi-fidelity prototypes. Ensured the Styleguide, Accessibility, SEO, Performance guidelines were adopted across all applications.

Helped coding React components and layout templates that followed markup and styling best practices

MAIN PROJECTS: Sky Store for Web, Mobile, and TV Devices

SAPO PORTUGAL TELECOM Apr 2013 - Jan 2016

#### **USER EXPERIENCE SPECIALIST**

Conducted the user-centered design process of some of SAPO's main web projects.

Designed field studies' protocols and questionnaires.

Performed heuristic evaluations of SAPO's and partner's products.

Designed low-fidelity to mid-fidelity prototypes to be validated and used as UI design and development reference.

Conducted card sorting and usability test sessions with users.

Developed and analysed the results of A/B and Multivariate tests.

Ensured Accessibility, SEO, and Performance guidelines were adopted.

MAIN PROJECTS: SAPO Mag | SAPO Biz | SAPO Blogs | SAPO Vídeos | SAPO Promos | SAPO UX

MLDC MICROSOFT PORTUGAL Jan 2011 - Mar 2013

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER / RESEARCHER

Researched on Natural User Interaction and Human-Computer Interaction. Conducted field studies with elderly to discover connectivity habits and needs, to inform the development of a multimodal digital personal assistant. Specified, prototyped, validated and developed desktop, mobile, and web projects.

Conducted usability studies with users, both elderly and mobility-impaired.

MAIN PROJECTS: Living Usability Lab | AAL4ALL | PaeLife | Living Home Center Prototype

Birth

Phone (+351) 968784447

Email

vsdteixeira@gmail.com

Website

LinkedIn

inkedin.com/in/vsdteixeira

## Skillset

Design Ecoder ship
Discovery / Research
Prototyping
Usability testing
Heuristic evaluation
Interaction design

#### Toolkit

Sketch / Figma HTML / CSS / JS Brain, Pen and Pape

## Hobbies

Movies & TV Shows Hardboiled Literature DiY / Handywork Barbecuing

## Languages

PORTUGUESE

**ENGLISH** 

SPANISH



# VÍTOR TEIXEIRA

#### USER EXPERIENCE PROFESSIONAL

### EDUCATION & TRAINING

COACHING

CONTINUOUS PRODUCT DISCOVERY

Nov 2018 - Feb 2019 Teresa Torres - Product Talk

12 weeks coaching on how to adopt a regular cadence of customer interviews, rapid prototyping, and product experiments, all in service of driving product outcomes.

Discovery coaching summary

UX COURSES

NIELSEN NORMAN GROUP UX COURSES

Nov 2018 NN/g - Nielsen Norman Group

Application Design for Web and Desktop

The Human Mind and Usability

The One-Person UX Team Tool Box

CERTIFICATION

CERTIFIED SCRUM MASTER (CSM)

Apr 2018

Scrum Alliance

 $16\mbox{-}hour \, course taught by a Certified Scrum Trainer (CST), followed by a CSM certification test.$ 

Scrum Alliance Profile

DEGREE & MASTER OF SCIENCE 2006 - 2011

TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND INFORMATION SCIENCE

ISCTE - University Institute of Lisbon (ISCTE-IUL)

Dissertation on the impact, in the elderly population, of multimodal graphical user interfaces for interacting with communication services and social networks.

Dissertation PDF (3.6 MB)